# **Ntim Obed Yeboah**

Senior Back-end Software Engineer

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ntimyeboah

https://github.com/NtimYeboah

https://medium.com/@ntimyeboah

Accra, Ghana ntimobedyeboah@gmail.com +233 209106049

Software developer with 7+ years of experience and track record in web applications development. I have expertise in creating modern web applications with PHP, an open-source software maintainer, and a Certified Laravel Developer.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, 64 Robots - Sept 2018 - Present - Baltimore, USA

- Helped the team build and deployed to production both the API endpoints and admin panel for <a href="Boombox">Boombox</a>, gift giver's collaboration application.
- Built and deployed to production the donation feature using Stripe for <u>ADRA</u> payment system.
- Helped design the database schema and implemented endpoints for NCIC messaging application.
- → Built and deployed to production OAuth2 server for Redflag Mania gamify e-learning platform's integration with Western Governor University e-learning platform.
- Built the admin panel and wrote <u>developer's documentation</u> for <u>Lauded</u>, reviews curation application.
- → Maintain ordinance checks application called <u>Signcode</u> for a client.
- → Help the team build <u>Remate</u> for making remote work easier for all.
- → Built and maintain <u>64 Robots stripe open-source package</u>.

# Full-Stack Developer, Kudobuzz - Sept 2017 - July 2018 - Accra, Ghana

- → Led the development of the merchant dashboard for the latest version of Kudobuzz.
- → Built and deployed the latest version of the <u>Kudobuzz WordPress plugin</u>.
- → Built the latest version of SEO Minisite for merchants.

# Software Developer, Callens Solutions - May 2016 - Aug 2017 - Accra, Ghana

- → Led the development of CRM software for a client that deals in hire purchase of electronic products.
- → Built an online shopping application for hire purchase of electronic products for a client partnering with Barclays Bank Ghana.
- → Built a mobile application counterpart for the online shopping application.

# Mobile Applications Developer, Yame Service - Nov 2015 - March 2016 - Tema, Ghana

→ Built utility payments solutions on mobile using the lonic Framework

### **Software Developer, Coursedub** *Aug 2014 - Oct 2015 -* Accra, Ghana

I was part of a team that built an e-learning software to connect teachers and students after lectures.

#### **OPEN SOURCE PROJECT**

<u>Laravel database trigger</u>: A package to generate database trigger migration files for Laravel applications.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Tech Stack: PHP/Laravel Framework, Javascript/Node/VueJs, Laravel Vapor, Laravel Forge

Database: MYSQL

Cache: Redis

# **EDUCATION**

2013 B.Sc. Computer Science, <u>University for Development Studies</u>, Tamale, Ghana

→ Built book recommendation software for students based on courses registered for the semester as a final year dissertation project.

### OTHER CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Laravel Developer - Sept. 2018

The Data Scientist's Toolbox - John Hopkins University, Coursera - Feb. 2016

# **LANGUAGES**

English